Contact

+972525344907 (Mobile) sergey@bolshchikov.net

www.linkedin.com/in/bolshchikov (LinkedIn) bolshchikov.net (Personal)

boishchikov.net (Personal)

Top Skills

JavaScript
Web Development
Software Development

Languages

Python (Professional Working)
Ruby (Elementary)
JavaScript (Full Professional)

Honors-Awards

Opportunity Grant from Public Affairs Section of US Embassy

University Exhibition of Students Inventions and Software

Publications

Modeling and Simulation-based Systems Engineering Handbook

Visualizing the Dynamics of Conceptual Behavior Models: The Vivid OPM Scene Player

Patents

Computer-Aided Information System "ECHO"

Sergey Bolshchikov

Software Engineer & Manager

Summary

I have a proven experience of designing, building products from ground up; managing development under real user traffic with 100k requests traffic.

I know how to build and scale a team who will continue building products.

I know how to mentor each team member to teach their own next milestone.

Experience

Wix.com
Engineering Manager
April 2018 - Present
Tel Aviv, Israel

Being engineering manager at Wix for the Front End Engineering group our goal is to create the place for over 350 front-end developers can grow, deliver and excel!.

This includes the range of different spheres like recruitment, onboarding, education, communication, branding, engineering and more.

You Gotta Love Frontend Conference Co-Founder August 2014 - Present

Tel Aviv, Israel

Organizing the best FED's event in Israel and Middle East ever.

Wix.com

3 years 11 months

Team Lead

June 2016 - May 2018 (2 years)

Israe

Growing a team from 5 to 12 developers. Together we've built and design a new back office platform that hosts over 30 applications.

Technical Lead

June 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Tel Aviv Area, Israel

Design and implement invoices application under the family of CRM products.

Software Engineer

July 2014 - June 2015 (1 year)

Design and implement from ground up the news feed cms.

Refactor news feed app.

New Prolmage LTD

2 years 2 months

Senior Front-End Engineer

July 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Israel

Developing application framework for the large-scale real-time application with the use of design patterns (mediator, facade, module), requirejs, web sockets, Ember.js, SVG and Canvas technologies.

Building automated testing system with NodeJS, PhantomJS and Jasmine for unit-testing.

Writing open-source Ember.js components library.

Frontend Engineer

June 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Israel

Design and implement the framework for the rich web client application.

Extensive research of Javascript MVC frameworks, GUI frameworks, Single-page application.

http://www.slideshare.net/bolshchikov/js-web-app-essentials

Education

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

MSc, Information Systems · (2009 - 2013)

Ural State Technical University

Engineer's degree, Information Systems in Medicine · (2004 - 2009)

Music School #4

Diploma, Piano · (1994 - 2003)